Muhammad Asif

A highly talented, knowledgeable, and dedicated finance and corporate professional with demonstrated track record of providing exquisite accounting, finance and corporate affairs services. Having over 10 years of experience in accounting, finance, internal audit, taxation, costing, corporate and secretarial practices in different public listed and un-listed companies. A great communicator with people from all social, professional, and cultural backgrounds. Well mannered, articulate and fully aware of diversity and multicultural issues as well as corporate rules and etiquette. Adapts quickly to new environments and thrives on multiple tasks.





0092 (0) 3157992134 0092 (0) 3212593974



masif1508@gmail.com



2003 - 2013

F-307, 3rd Floor, Anam Palace, Near Custom House, Karachi

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

July 2014 -Present

Financial Controller and Deputy Company Secretary

The Resource Group (TRG) | Karachi

Lead a team of corporate finance professionals to the following key areas:

- Prepare scenario based financial models, cash flow projections, data analytics, and other financial planning and analysis (FP&A), using different business intelligence tools (BI) to support decision making of group management and BOD.
- Coordinate annual and half yearly national / international regulatory audits of the group and preparing filing, publishing separate financial statements (FS) with subsidiary reported at fair value, consolidated FS of 45 entities and FS for an investment entity opting consolidation exemption under IFRS 10.
- Handled due diligence and advised management on contracts, investment and regulatory actions including business combination (merger, acquisition, IPO etc.) transactions.
- Supervise payments and taxation matters including filing of statements and returns.
- Supervise treasury matters and dealing with banks for negotiations of terms and conditions.
- Supervise all corporate affairs matters of holding company listed in Pakistan Stock Exchange (PSX).
- Handling correspondence with SECP, PSX, CDC, SBP, FBR, Shares Registrar and shareholders.
- Review NDA and other legal agreements and petitions.

Dec 2013 -April 2014

Manager Internal Audit & Compliance

Habib Assets Management Co. Ltd. | Karachi

Responsible for the maintenance of effective and efficient internal controls over the business processes of both the Management Company and open and closed end Mutual Funds. Ensure compliance with the relevant laws and regulations. Also responsible for preparation of audit and compliance reports, notices and minutes of Audit Committee meetings.

EDUCATION

Cost and Management Accountant (ACMA) Major: Accounting, Finance, Costing

Institute of Cost and Management Accountant of Pakistan

(Main Campus, Full-Time, Postgraduate Course. The Business School has ranked Top 10 Business Schools in Pakistan)

Modules:

Accounting, Finance, Financial Reporting, International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS), Costing, Taxation, Internal Audit, Corporate Law.

2002 - 2004

Masters in Arts: M.A. Major: Economics

1999 - 2000 **Bachelor of Commerce:** B.Com.

Major: Accounting and **Finance**

LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu

MEMBERSHIPS

- Institute of Cost and Management Accountants of Pakistan
- Institute of Public Finance Accountants of Pakistan

March 2013-Nov 2013

Head of Fund Services

Standard Chartered Bank (Pakistan) Ltd. | Karachi

- Supervision of Funds Services and Securities Services Departments and ensure that operations are within the guidelines and in compliance with regulatory requirements and bank's established procedures.
- Check all designated areas of operations with vigilance and care to ensure customers receive the highest standard of quality services at all times.
- Support local product and sales team in client meetings.
- Coordinate and audit of peer review of other country's securities services department.

Aug 2007-Jan 2013

AVP Finance and Company Secretary

Summit Bank Limited | Karachi

Lead a team of finance professionals to the following key areas:

- Supervision of financial reporting, consolidation budgeting, financial modeling, financial analysis, payments, prepayments and fixed assets schedules, branch accounting, taxation, SBP reporting, managed chart of accounts, nostro and sundry nature accounts reconciliations.
- Supervision of provident fund (PF) and gratuity fund
- Treasury matters of PF and GF.
- Corporate Affairs matters of the Bank.

Accomplishment:

Listing and IPO of the bank, merger and acquisitions of two banks with and into Summit Bank, hPlus implementation in head office and branch levels, centralize tax payment and reporting mechanism.

Aug 2005-Aug 2007

Assistant Manager Finance

Alfalah GHP Investment Management Ltd. | Karachi

- Responsible for R2R, preparation of financial statements, annual budgets, financial plans.
- Preparation of daily NAVs, monthly and annual tax statements, tax returns, bank and GL reconciliations, SECP, SBP, MUFAP reporting, monthly payroll, management fee working, commission working.
- Liaison with banks on different matters, coordinate with internal and external auditors, coordinate with credit rating agency for credit rating, corporate affairs matters.

Dec 2004-

Assistant Manager Accounts

Aug 2005

Noble Computers (Pvt.) Ltd. | Karachi

Responsible for R2R, preparation of financial statements, payroll, submission of tax statements and returns, monitoring of invoicing, payments and recovery, dealing with banks, corporate affairs matters.

Feb 1996-Nov 2004

Accounts Officer

Modaraba Association of Pakistan | Karachi

Responsible for R2R, preparation of financial statements, payroll, submission of tax statements and returns, monitoring of invoicing, payments and recovery, dealing with banks, corporate affairs matters.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Consolidation
- Financial Reporting and Analysis
- Budgeting and Forecasting
- Cash flow forecast and cost controlling
- R2R
- FP&A
- Financing arrangements from banks
- Raise equity and loan from public market
- Taxation
- Internal Audit and Compliance review
- Mergers and Acquisitions
- Due Diligence
- Communications
- Team Building and Management
- Company formation, listing, IPOs
- Microsoft Office, Microsoft Dynamics, SHAMA GL, Oracle, Peachtree, Quickbook, Tally, hPlus, Mysis, AB-II
- ERP implementation

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

- I.T. Sector
- NBFC and NBFI
- Banking
- Shares Registrar
- NPO

TRAININGS

- Attended one weeks training in Dubai on Fund Services
- Attended workshop of financial modeling
- Participated in training on corporate governance organized by IBP

INTERNATIONAL FREELANCE EXPERIENCES

- Saudi Arabia
- UAE

REFERENCES

Will be furnished on request